Alexander Bartley Nees

Software Developer 027 8193553

<u>alexbartleynees@gmail.com</u> <u>http://www.linkedin.com/in/alex-bartley-nees</u> <u>https://github.com/alex-bartleynees</u>

About Me

I am a software developer who takes pride and pleasure in crafting beautiful code and learning new skills. I was previously a brewer, working at Kereru Brewing Company for five years, and winning numerous awards. I have always valued self-learning and taught myself brewing which led to my employment in the industry. I returned to study in 2019 to pursue a degree in Philosophy after developing an interest in Buddhist philosophy. I love thinking deeply about big ideas and studying philosophy has honed my critical, creative and logical thinking and research skills.

My enthusiasm for problem-solving and deep thinking led me to software development. I studied for 15 weeks at Enspiral Dev Academy where I learnt the foundations of web development and worked on numerous group projects including an online game, as well as personal projects. Studying at Dev Academy reinforced my commitment to a career in IT, my interest in coding and my enjoyment of learning. I demonstrated my commitment to success by studying 60 hours a week to develop my coding skills while at the same time working on my human (soft) skills advancing my ability to work and communicate effectively in a team. Throughout the course I strived for a full understanding of what I was learning and the code I was writing driven by my underlying passion for philosophy which involves asking deep questions.

I am a curious, calm and quiet person who has demonstrated the ability to succeed in any area to which I apply myself.

I.T Skills

Front-end: HTML, CSS, Handlebars, React, Redux, Gatsby

Back-end: Node.js, Express.is, Sglite3, PostgreSgl, Web APIs, GraphQL

Programming: Javascript

Other: Git, Agile

The Bootcamp at Enspiral Dev Academy had a strong emphasis on full-stack web development focusing on Javascript, React/Redux, and Node.js and I developed these skills throughout the course by working on group and personal projects.

Experience

February - May 2021: Enspiral Dev Academy Wellington

Student Web Developer

Enspiral Dev Academy is an intensive 15 weeks web development Bootcamp that replicates a real-life working environment and focuses on building web development skills as well as a focus on pair programming and group projects to develop teamwork and interpersonal skills. My final group project involved working on an online game version of "Mafia" and I also worked on numerous personal projects including a meditation web app to track how much time I was spending meditating. Check it out here: https://meditationtracker.herokuapp.com/

- I worked as an Agile lead on my final group project where I communicated with the team
 to ensure we were working with the agile values of open communication, flexibility and
 trust, as well as using agile practices, such as standups. This was important for us as we
 were using web sockets, which was a new technology for us, meaning we needed
 flexibility and to be able to trust each other in our roles in order to solve problems.
- Improved my ability to work and communicate effectively as part of a team through working on group projects each week and pair programming.
- Developed an understanding of the front-end technologies of React, Redux, Javascript, HTML and CSS and the back-end technologies Node.js, databases, Sqlite3 and PostgreSql.
- Check out my final group project Midnight Mysteries https://midnight-mysteries.herokuapp.com/

March 2019 - January 2021: Part-time Cleaner

March 2014 - 2019: Kereru Brewing Company

- Recipe Development- creating award-winning beers
- Won Trophy for Feijoa Weisse at 2019 Brewers Guild Awards
- Won Champion Small International Brewery at Australian International Beer Awards 2018. I am often a perfectionist and obsess over small details and at Kereru I paid a lot of attention to recipe development and perfecting our brewing process which paid off with this award.
- Worked effectively as part of a team including training new brewers.
- Daily operation and oversight of the brewhouse and fermentation process.

2008 - 2013 Moore Wilson's Fresh, Tory Street, Wellington

 Part-time and holiday work during weekends and university vacation, mainly in Produce and Beer & Wine sections.

Voluntary work

2017 - 2019 Volunteering at Buddhist retreats2010, 2012 Beervana volunteer

Education

Victoria University of Wellington, 2019 - 2020

Bachelor of Arts in Philosophy

Victoria University's 2019 and 2020 Dean's List for Academic Excellence.

New Zealand School of Music, 2010 - 2012

Completed three years of study at the New Zealand School of Music from 2010 - 2012. (Left to pursue employment opportunity).

Institute Of Brewing and Distilling:

General Certificate in Brewing Diploma of Brewing Module 1 Diploma of Brewing Module 2

Student exchange to Italy 2008 - 2009.

Hobbies/Interests

My main interests are Tibetan Buddhism and Buddhist philosophy. I've been seriously practicing Buddhism for the last four years and it has become a huge part of my life. Other interests include film. I have a keen interest in learning about the world and I love how film can portray experiences and aspects of life that are very different to our own. I often attend the Wellington Film Society. I am also an avid practitioner of yoga because it makes my body and mind feel really good and helps me let go of negative emotions and stress.

References available on request.